hello@rhjones.me 785-727-8485

REBEKAH HEACOCK JONES

Senior engineer with 4+ years of experience leading the development of complex web-based applications. Proficient at backend tasks (API development, data modeling, query optimization) and UI development. Passionate about quality code, user experience, and engineer education.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ENGINEER

Wayfair

Senior Engineer (III)
Sept 2018-present
Software Engineer II
Mar 2018-Sept 2018
Software Engineer I
Jan 2017-Mar 2018

- Architected and led team of 7 to build platform (PHP, JS, C#/.NET) for supplier wholesale cost discount negotiations. Brought in ~\$3.5m in new revenue monthly, on average.
- Designed and built set of web applications and automated processes to track, analyze, and approve ~\$500m of internal costs annually (previously handled manually in Excel). Reduced person hours required to manage these costs by 70%.
- Automated import and reconciliation process for non-customer-facing transactions/invoices. Integrated with 3rd party APIs and wrote matching algorithm to reconcile transactions and invoices. Reconciliation accuracy increased from 76 to 97%; cut time to reconcile from over 30 days to less than 2.
- Led team to increase automated test code coverage in PHP and JS/React from 0 to 40% in six months.
- Developed company-wide technical guidelines (PHP/JS/SQL) and build/test/deploy training for incoming engineers.

COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Harvard Extension School Spring & Fall 2016

SR PROJECT MANAGER

Berkman Klein Center for Internet & Society, Harvard 2010-2016

- TA for CSCI E-15: object-oriented PHP using Laravel, basic server set up and management, and Git.
- Developed course materials; led 25-person weekly lab; graded projects; offered individual tutoring on Slack.
- Worked closely with engineers and stakeholders to scope, build, and test two of the Center's largest software projects to date (dp.la and thenetmonitor.org).
- Wrote technical guides and API documentation.
- Managed team of technical project coordinators.

EDUCATION

HARVARD EXTENSION SCHOOL

- Intensive Introduction to Computer Science
- Dynamic Web Applications
- Introduction to Web Programming Using JavaScript

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive

Built four full stack web applications in 12 weeks using Ruby on Rails,

Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Ember.

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY

Master of International Affairs

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS

Honors BA, Slavic Languages & Literatures

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, React/Redux, T-SQL/MySQL, REST, PHPUnit, Jest, Enzyme, Agile, Git